<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Forvision project on the Forvision project</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Forvision project on the Forvision project</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Time Series (TSTS)</title>
      <link>/approach/data-structures/tsts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/approach/data-structures/tsts/</guid>
      <description>In time series table schema each observation is stored in a table as a separate record (line):
   Field name (column name) Description Examples     *series_id Time series identifier - a unique name that identifies a time series “Y1”   *timestamp Any representation of the period to which the observation relates “01.01.1997” in case of daily data, “Sep 1997” in case of monthly data, “Week 49, 1997” in case of weekly data   value The value observed 1000    *the key (the unique value that should not duplicated) for this table schema is series_id, timestamp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forecast (FTS)</title>
      <link>/approach/data-structures/fts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/approach/data-structures/fts/</guid>
      <description>Forecast Table Schema is needed to store forecasting results.
Each table line corresponds to all the forecasting results obtained for a given time series series using a given method for a given horizon for a given origin:
   Field name (column name) Description Examples     series_id* Time series identifier - a unique name that identifies a time series “Y1”   period_timestamp Any representation of the period to which the observation relates “01.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Actuals and forecasts(AFTS)</title>
      <link>/approach/data-structures/afts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/approach/data-structures/afts/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes it is convenient to have a table where we have both actuals and forecasts in one row in one table. This Actuals and Forecasts Table Schema (AFTS) is the same as the FTS schema, but additional column “value” is used to represent the actual value of time series. If no actual value is available, then “value”=”NA”.
In order to obtain data in the AFTS format, we can use a query to link actual values from the TSTS schema and forecasts from the FTS schema: diagram</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prediction-Realization Diagram</title>
      <link>/approach/exploratory-tools.md/prd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/approach/exploratory-tools.md/prd/</guid>
      <description>The function plotPRD of the forvision package plots the Prediction-Realization Diagram for the given data from dataset containing columns actual, forecast, and method (AFTS).
Here’s a prediction-realization diagram created by the function plotPRD:
library(forvision) plotPRD(AFTS)  The resulting prediction-relization digram plotted in logarithmic scales by using the option setting useLog ==TRUE:
library(forvision) plotPRD(AFTS, useLogs = TRUE)  The prediction-realization diagram for the selected methods:
# For the methods &amp;quot;ARARMA&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Auto-ANN&amp;quot;, and &amp;quot;DAMPEN&amp;quot; data1 &amp;lt;- subset(AFTS, method == c(&amp;quot;ARARMA&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Auto-ANN&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;DAMPEN&amp;quot;)) library(forvision) plotPRD(data1)  The prediction-realization diagram for the selected horizon:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fanchart</title>
      <link>/approach/exploratory-tools.md/fanchart/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/approach/exploratory-tools.md/fanchart/</guid>
      <description>The function plotFAN of the forvision package plots the fanchart for the given data from dataset.
Here’s a fanchart created by the function plotFAN for time series of id == &amp;ldquo;M1&amp;rdquo;:
library(forvision) plotFAN(ts = TSTS, fc = AFTS, id = &amp;quot;M1&amp;quot;)  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fixed origin graph</title>
      <link>/approach/exploratory-tools.md/fixed-origin-graph/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/approach/exploratory-tools.md/fixed-origin-graph/</guid>
      <description>The function plotFS of the forvision package plots the fixed origin graph for the given data from dataset.
Here’s a fixed origin graph created by the function plotFS for time series of id == &amp;ldquo;M1&amp;rdquo;:
library(forvision) plotFS(fc = AFTS1, id = &amp;quot;M1&amp;quot;)  The fixed origin graph with the forecasts of the single forecast method by using the option setting method:
library(forvision) plotFS(fc = AFTS1, id = &amp;quot;M1&amp;quot;, method = &amp;quot;AutoBox1&amp;quot;)  The fixed origin graph with the forecasts of the multiple forecast methods by using the option setting method:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fixed horizon graph</title>
      <link>/approach/exploratory-tools.md/fixed-horizon-graph/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/approach/exploratory-tools.md/fixed-horizon-graph/</guid>
      <description>Fixed horizon graph</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Point forecasts evaluation</title>
      <link>/approach/accuracy-tools/point-forecast-evaluation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/approach/accuracy-tools/point-forecast-evaluation/</guid>
      <description>Mean absolute percentage error for different forecasting methods and different horizons is generated using the function calculateMAPEs of the forvision package for the given data from dataset.
library(forvision) calculateMAPEs(afts)  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PIs evaluation</title>
      <link>/approach/accuracy-tools/pis-evaluation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/approach/accuracy-tools/pis-evaluation/</guid>
      <description>The Validation of PIs is generated using the function validatePIs of the forvision package for the given data from dataset:
library(forvision) validatePIs(afts)  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Test cases</title>
      <link>/datasets/test-cases/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/datasets/test-cases/</guid>
      <description>Example 1
In this example we have data containing actuals for several time time series + corresponding out-of-sample forecasts with different horizons produced using different forecasting methods at different origins.
   File Description Schema     example1_tsts.csv Actual observations TSTS (Time Series Table Schema)   example1_afts.csv Actuals and forecasts AFTS (Forecast Table Schema)    To cite this website, please use the following reference:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>M3-Competition data</title>
      <link>/datasets/m3-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/datasets/m3-data/</guid>
      <description>The 3003 time series from the IJF-M3 competition (Makridakis and Hibon, 2000) and M3 Data with Rolling-Origin and Interval Forecasts saved as csv files
   File Description Schema     FORAYearSeries.csv The yearly time series from the M3 forecasting competition TSTS (Time Series Table Schema)   FORAYearForecast.csv The yearly forecasts of yearly time series from all the original participating methods in the M3 forecasting competition AFTS (Forecast Table Schema)   FORAQuartSeries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to download and install</title>
      <link>/forvision/install/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/forvision/install/</guid>
      <description>Installation You can install the development version of the forvision package (containing the latest improvements and bug fixes) from github:
# install.packages(&amp;#34;devtools&amp;#34;) devtools::install_github(&amp;#34;forvis/forvision&amp;#34;) Problems and Issues Please report any issues you may encounter in our issues page on github</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Loading data</title>
      <link>/forvision/load-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/forvision/load-data/</guid>
      <description>Read data from URL (from example datasets) You can use the following methods to read data from URL sources:
1) Using function download.file():
temporaryFile &amp;lt;- tempfile() download.file(&amp;quot;RUL&amp;quot;, destfile=temporaryFile) myData &amp;lt;- read.csv(temporaryFile)  2) Using package RCurl:
library(RCurl) myCsv &amp;lt;- getURL(&amp;quot;RUL&amp;quot;, ssl.verifypeer = FALSE) myData &amp;lt;- read.csv(textConnection(myCsv))  3) Using R base function read.csv():
myData &amp;lt;- read.csv(&amp;quot;RUL&amp;quot;)  You can use the RULs for examples datasets from the section datasets</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data integrity checks</title>
      <link>/forvision/data-check/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/forvision/data-check/</guid>
      <description>This page is under construction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploratory analysis</title>
      <link>/forvision/exploratory-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/forvision/exploratory-analysis/</guid>
      <description>This page is under construction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accuracy evaluation</title>
      <link>/forvision/accuracy-evaluation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/forvision/accuracy-evaluation/</guid>
      <description>This page is under construction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project team</title>
      <link>/team/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/team/</guid>
      <description>Sai Van Cuong: PhD student of CAD Department, Volgograd State Technical University
Dr. Andrey Davydenko: Data Science Specialist, JSC CSBI
Prof. Shcherbakov Maxim: Head of CAD Department, Volgograd State Technical University</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>